Prepare to get served.
Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs is a animation, comedy,
family film directed by Christopher Miller.
Inventor Flint Lockwood creates a machine that makes clouds rain food, enabling
the down-and-out citizens of Chewandswallow to feed themselves.
But when the falling food reaches gargantuan proportions,
Flint must scramble to avert disaster.
Can he regain control of the machine and put an end to the
wild weather before the town is destroyed?
Flint Lockwood (voice), played by Bill Hader.
Sam Sparks (voice), played by Anna Faris.
Tim Lockwood (voice), played by James Caan.
"Baby" Brent (voice), played by Andy Samberg.
Mayor Shelbourne (voice), played by Bruce Campbell.
Earl Devereaux (voice), played by Mr. T.
Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs is a 2009 American animated science fiction comedy film written and directed by
Phil Lord and Christopher Miller, loosely based on the 1978 children's book by Judi and Ron Barrett.
It was produced by Columbia Pictures and Sony Pictures Animation, and stars the voices
of Bill Hader, Anna Faris, James Caan, Andy Samberg, Bruce Campbell, Mr.
T, Benjamin Bratt, and Neil Patrick Harris.
The film centers around an aspiring inventor named Flint Lockwood who develops, following a
series of failed experiments, a machine that can convert water into food.
After the machine becomes rogue and begins to develop food
storms, Flint must stop it in order to save the world.
Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs premiered at the Mann Village Theater in Los Angeles on September 12,
2009, and was released in the United States on September 18 by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It was a box office success, grossing $243 million against a budget of $100M.
The film received positive reviews from critics and was nominated for
Best Animated Feature at the 67th Golden Globe Awards.
A sequel, Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs 2, was released in 2013,
while an animated television series premiered in 2017.
The film explores themes of inventor, weather, food,
based on children's book, hopeful.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting.